VENKATA LAHARI BALANTRAPU

MSc Artificial Intelligence And Machine Learning

Optimistic and Self-Learning enthusiast in the Field of Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence. Hardworking and driven individual with skills looking forward to further enhance the knowledge and gain experience working with real life problems.

Work History

2021-06 -Current

Research Intern

Gendoo Lab, Birmingham, England

- Validating clustering techniques to analyse correlation between cancer gene expression of patients against Xenografts and Organoids.
- Coding work being performed using R language.
- Planning and executing research techniques, procedures and tests.

2020-11 -Current

Student Ambassador

University of Birmingham, Birmingham, ENG

- Interacted with university and prospective students and parents during tours and student visit days, answering questions and providing insight.
- Moderated closely as a team with students in assisting future applicants resulted in enhanced group dynamics along with communication skills and time management.
- Answered questions, pointed out important features, and offered suggestions about pre requisites of course.

Education

2020-09 -Current

MSc: Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning

University of Birmingham - Birmingham

Modules:

• Neural Computation, Mathematical Foundations of Al

Contact

Address

Birmingham, UK, B151EQ

Phone

+447737282441.

E-mail

laharibalantrapu@gmail.co m

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lahari-balantrapu-55944420

WWW

https://github.com/ivyaeri

Skills

Python, SQL, Java, C

Machine Learning, Image Processing, Computer Vision

Matlab, Sckiti-learn, Tensorflow, Jupyter, OpenCV

Problem Solving, Analytical Thinking

Data Collection, Processing

Languages

English (Proficient).

and ML, Computer Vision, Visualization, Machine learning and Intelligent Data Analysis.

Coding course works:

• Backpropagation and SoftMax on fashion MINST, 11/2020 -12/2020. • Semantic-Segmentation of MR images using CNN, 12/2020.

- University Admission Prediction Using Linear Regression without inbuilt functions, 11/2020–12/2020.
- Image Processing basic methodologies using MATLAB, Mar 2021.

Dissertation: Automatic segmentation of covid 19 CT scans.

2016-06 -2020-09

Bachelor of Technology: Computer Science

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University - India

Class Rank: First class with Distinction

Modules:

• C, C++, Java, SQL, Python, R, Software Engineering, Data Mining, Machine learning, Design and Analysis of Algorithms.

Project: Skin Cancer Prediction Using Machine learning and OpenCV, 12/2019-03/2020.

Scholarships:

- Received a scholarship of 25,000rs awarded by Aditya Educational Institutions.
- Awarded a merit-based scholarship of 5000rs every year for outstanding performance in the curriculum.

Workshops

- Attained 'Python for Everybody' course complete certificate by UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN, COURSERA.
- Attended a two-day national level Seminar on 'Deep Learning for Bioinformatics' sponsored by NSERB INDIA.
- Active participant of a two-day workshop on 'BLOCK CHAIN TECHNOLOGY' conducted at JNTUK VIZIANAGARAM in association with ANVIRA EDUSTATION, AAKAAR IIT BOMBAY.

Telugu (Native).

Hindi (Proficient).